illuminas.com 2016-01-12

# Privacy Policy - Illuminas

#### **Our commitment to privacy**

Illuminas Global  (“Illuminas”) is a professional marketing intelligence agency that uses scientific methods to gain insight to specific issues relevant to our clients. Any information that you supply to Illuminas is used solely for legitimate research or statistical purposes and will never result in an attempt to sell you anything based on your responses. We strictly adhere to practices and guidelines that respect the individual’s right to privacy and extend the following assurances to all research projects:

#### **Notification:**

  * In obtaining your cooperation, we will not mislead you about the nature of the research or the use that will be made of the findings.
  * We will not send you unsolicited email or pass on your email address(es) to others for this purpose. If we want to send you future email or contact you using other methods, we will ask your explicit permission for this.
  * On rare occasions we may use cookies (A cookie is a piece of information that webservers send to your browser file when you access a website. Then when you come back to a website again, that website will detect whether you have a cookies on your browser file.)and other similar devices sparingly for quality control, validation, or to prevent bothersome repeat surveying. You can configure your browser to notify you when cookies are being placed on your computer or to reject cookies altogether. In addition to your responses, we automatically capture basic information about your online survey experience, including your device type, browser type and length of time responding to specific questions. We do no other invisible processing of your data, nor do we attempt to obtain any data from your computer or mobile device.
  * Illuminas has a network of third party vendors and they are contractually obligated to solely use your information for research and statistical purposes.

#### **Choice:**

  * Should you wish to opt out from future surveys, please notify us at via email at [solutions@illuminas.com](mailto:solutions@illuminas.com) or by writing the address noted below. It is our goal to respond to each email within one working day, but please allow 1-2 weeks for complete removal of your data.
  * All information you provide is confidential and reported anonymously. In rare occurrences, we may ask for permission to use certain responses in a form that would allow you to be personally identified. In such cases, this information will only be passed on with your expressed consent and only for the purposes stated.
  * Your cooperation is voluntary at all times. You are entitled at any stage of the interview or survey, or subsequently, to ask that part or all of your information be destroyed or deleted. Wherever reasonable and practical, we will carry out such a request.
  * We will not knowingly interview children (those under the age of 15) without first getting permission from their parent or guardian.

#### **Onward Transfer:**

  * All Third parties are contractually obligated to keep your information secure and intact.
  * Third parties are solely contracted to use the information provided for research or statistical purposes. No other use of your information is authorized.
  * Personal information may be disclosed to judicial or other government agencies subject to warrants, subpoenas, or other governmental orders.

#### **Access:**

  * Information collected by Illuminas is processed solely for research or statistical purposes. Due to the possible compromise to other respondents’ data/information, access to stored data will not be granted to individuals who participate in research efforts.
  * We encourage you to email [solutions@illuminas.com](mailto:solutions@illuminas.com) to address any concerns or questions you may have

#### **Security:**

  * Our web site and internal network has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control.
  * Only authorized employees and contractually bound partners have access to the information you provide to us. They have access solely for research, statistical analysis and quality control purposes.
  * Personal data is stored for twelve (12) months after each study is complete.
  * Illuminas does not sell or rent any personally identifiable information to third parties.
  * In the event of reorganization, merger, or sale, we may transfer any and all personal information to the relevant third party.
  * At no point does Illuminas have access to any personal credit card information.

#### **Data Integrity:**

  * Illuminas shall only process Personal Information in a way that is compatible with and relevant for the purpose for which it was collected or authorized by the individual
  * Illuminas shall take reasonable steps to ensure that Personal Information is accurate, complete, current and reliable for its intended use.

#### **Enforcement:**

  * Illuminas utilizes a self-assessment approach to assure compliance with this privacy policy and periodically verifies that the policy is accurate, comprehensive for the information intended to be covered, prominently displayed, completely implemented and accessible and in conformity with the principles. We encourage interested persons to raise any concerns using the contact information provided and we will investigate and attempt to resolve any complaints and disputes regarding use and disclosure of personal information in accordance with the principles.
  * If a complaint or dispute cannot be resolved through our internal process, we agree to dispute resolution using eTrust Privacy Services as a third party resolution provider. You can reach eTrust’s privacy complaint system at the following URL: <http://www.etrust.org/complaint/raise_privacy_complaint.php>

#### Amendments

This privacy policy may be amended from time to time consistent with the requirements of the Safe Harbor. We will post any revised policy on this website. This version of Illuminas’ privacy policy was last modified on December 30, 2013.

#### **Commitment to Protect**

****In accordance with our commitment to protect personal privacy, Illuminas adheres to the seven privacy principles and fifteen frequently asked questions (FAQs) of the U.S.-EU and U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Frameworks as developed by the U.S. Department of Commerce in consultation with the European Commission and the Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner of Switzerland. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view Illuminas’ certification, please visit  <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>

#### Contact Information

You may contact us at s[olutions@illuminas.com](mailto:solutions@illuminas.com)  or via mail at Attn: Privacy Policy, 3801 South Capital of Texas Hwy, Ste 200, Austin, TX 78704 to express or discuss any concerns with an individual survey or questions regarding our general research practices. We are members of the Marketing Research Association and Council of American Survey Research Organizations (CASRO), and follow their codes of conduct for market research. All research projects are also conducted in accordance with the provisions of the ICC/ESOMAR International Code of Marketing and Social Research Practice.
